(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T22:23:09.729825",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Turn up radio そう今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up the radio, I can hear it today too,
風に揺られ流れ出る Stereo
Stereo flowing, swayed by the wind,
語り刻む軽快な Rhythm
A brisk rhythm carving out the story,
想いをのせ届ける Rhyme
Delivering rhymes carrying my thoughts.
よく晴れた空の真下
Right beneath a clear sunny sky,
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
We aimed for a distant future.
Master key 握り締め出発
Grasping the master key, we set off,
雑踏の中 Kick down 一発
Kicking down amid the hustle and bustle.
今思う闘いの日々
Thinking back on those days of battle,
感謝することにあふれ出す慈悲
Overflowing with gratitude and mercy,
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That fierce conflict where we honed our skills,
今なお続くここは最前線
Still ongoing, this is the front line.
父から得た揺るぎない誇り
Unwavering pride gained from my father,
母がくれた大きな温もり
The immense warmth given by my mother,
キミにもらう温かい温もり
The warm comfort I receive from you,
明日への糧に生き抜くために
As nourishment for tomorrow, to survive.
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy, when the sky's gray.
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yeah, yeah, yo, ZEBRA KAMINARI Jr.
Yeah, yeah, yo, Zebra coming junior
Yeah, yeah, yo
俺は東京生まれHIP HOP育ち
Born and raised in Tokyo, grown up on hip-hop
悪そうな奴は大体友達
Most of the bad guys are basically my friends
悪そうな奴と大体同じ
Most of them are pretty much the same as the bad guys
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
This is the city I've walked through its backstreets
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に これにぞっこんに
Shibuya, Roppongi, even adolescence was early into this
カバンなら置きっぱなししてきた高校に
High school where I left my schoolbag behind
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
Seriously, I caused a lot of trouble for my parents, truly
だが時は経ち今じゃ雑誌のカヴァー
But time has passed, now on magazine covers
そこらじゅうで幅利かすDON DADA
Making a scene everywhere, Don Dada
マイク掴んだらマジでNo.1
Grab the mic and I'm seriously No.1
東京代表トップランカーだ
The top-ranking representative of Tokyo
そうこの地のこの国に生を授かり
Bestowed with life in this land, in this country
Jahに無敵のマイク預かり
Blessed by Jah with the ultimate mic
仲間たち親たちファンたちに今日も 感謝して進む荒れたオフロード
Moving forward on a rough off-road with gratitude today too
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yeah, yo, mic check 1, 2
Yeah, yo, mic check one, two
日出づる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the Land of the Rising Sun
今こうして踏み締める大地
The ground we tread upon right now
常に開く新しいPage 旅に出ようそれぞれのStage
Always opening a new page, heading on a journey to each stage
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Joy and gratitude intertwined here
共に奏でる真の理解者
True kindred spirits playing together in harmony
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Depicting the era without holding back
Pressureはねのけて乱反射
Pressure shrugs off and reflects wildly
注ぎ込もう溢れ出す感情
Overflowing emotions pouring in
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Affection that never fades on any day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
A battlefield we plunge into without flinching
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
Emblem of lilies blooming without ever withering
やさしい風抜ける昼下がり
A gentle afternoon breeze clearing up
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
An after-rain clearing where a rainbow peeked out
陽の光映した水たまり 日々の喜びここに讃美
Puddles reflecting sunlight, praising daily joy here
この胸の高鳴りを 歌にのせて
This heart's swelling beat, put it into song
日々ここにあるもの この手に感じて
What is here every day, feel it in these hands
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
ZEBRA KAMINARI Jr. と共に進もう
Zebra coming junior, let's move forward together
ルパン
Lupin
ルパン三世
Lupin the Third
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire
let me show your my everything
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジー見てない
You haven't seen this dream's fantasy yet
今こそ走る時なんだ (it's show time)
Now is the time to run, it's show time
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me there, it's a one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足りないよ
This amount of trial is not enough
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want is not things, I steal your heart
Listen! Party people!
僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
I'm running through life at top speed
まるでスキーの直滑降
Like a straight downhill ski run
核弾頭 決めたことには頑固
Nuclear warhead, stubborn in what I've decided
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない
I don't know anything about living slowly
ここはステージ 遠慮はいらない
This is a stage, no hesitation needed
やることはやりますわ
What I have to do, I'll just do it
高みの山目指せ
Aim for the mountain peak
Put your hands up in the air!
僕を見つめる君はセクシー
You who gaze at me are sexy
甘く溶けるまるでチェルシー
Sweetly melting like chocolate, like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻き上げる様
The sight of you brushing back your hair with your hand
僕にとっての女王様
My queen,
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
I'll hold you tight tonight,
あと熱い唇をいただく
and take your passionate lips.
そして何よりも欲しいのよ
And above all else, what I want most
あなたの心 狂おしいほど
is your heart, driving me crazy.
It's a party night, dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance, let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Whether it's a thorny path,
凍てつく夜だろうが
or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
the impossible becomes possible with the two of us,
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually acting like a goofy fool,
誰も手にしたことないお宝貰う
I'll claim a treasure no one's ever touched.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
The target I lock onto won't escape,
それがなんだろうと驚こう
whatever it might be, prepare to be amazed!
先の先まで計算立てて 瞬時にひらめく名案
Calculating every move far in advance, a brilliant idea flashes instantly,
そして「あっ！」と思ったらもう居ない もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美学
and once you think "Ah!", I'm already gone—a theft aesthetic bordering on art.
Put your hands up in the air!
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this fantasy of dreams!
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time!)
This is the moment to run (It's show time!)
ルパン三世
Lupin the Third,
そこで見てて王様ンショー
watch from there, the one-man show,
これくらいの試練じゃ足らないよ
this much of a trial isn't enough!
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't material things, I steal your heart!
絶対逃がさんぞ
I'll never let you escape!
誰かが居ないと張り合えない
Without someone there, there's no competing,
相手が居てこそ間違い無い
and with a rival, there's no doubt.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival close by,
競い合い互いにハイになる
competing makes us both hyped up!
ファイナルステージだ天王山 お前との勝負の演奏さ
The final stage, the decisive battle, playing out our match!
マジで今夜はサシで どっちが勝ても文句はナシだぜ
Seriously, it's one-on-one tonight, no complaints no matter who wins!
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす僕はワルさ
Wielding my Walther, I'm bad.
曲がったこと嫌いプラスアルファ
Hating crooked things, plus alpha,
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
rap master, even Jedi are no match,
しかし可愛い女に目がない oh baby
but I've got a weak spot for cute girls, oh baby!
それは演技？or本気？ 僕は君に一本気
Is that acting? Or for real? I'm dead serious about you!
一本道走り続けてます 空へ飛ばす 今日から明日
Running straight ahead, soaring to the sky, from today to tomorrow!
It's a party night, dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance, let's go just do it!
Let's go just do it! 茨の道だろうが
Let's go just do it! Whether it's a thorny path,
凍てつく夜だろうが
or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
the impossible becomes possible, just the two of us, Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything 夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Let me show you my everything, look at this fantasy of dreams!
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time!)
This is the moment to run (It's show time!)
そこで見てて王様ンショー
Watch from there, the one-man show,
これくらいの試練じゃ足らないよ
this much of a trial isn't enough!
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない あなたのハート
What I want isn't material things, your heart!
愛すべき仲間や家族がいる
There are beloved friends and family,
信念やプライドを曲げずに貫くべし！
holding fast to convictions and pride without bending!
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything 眩しい眼差しを受けて
Let me show you my everything, receiving that dazzling gaze,
君のために今日を捨てるよ (It's show time!)
I'll throw away today for your sake (It's show time!)
世界で一人の最愛の君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings to you, my one and only love in the world!
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない あなたのハート (Yay!)
What I want isn't material things, your heart (Yay!)
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually acting like a goofy fool,
やる時は誰より真剣で
when it's time, more serious than anyone.
頼りになるいざという時 こうありたい誰が見ても素敵
Reliable in a pinch, this is how I want to be, wonderful to everyone's eyes.
知性備えたスーパーマン 横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
Superman equipped with intellect, right beside him the classic Superwoman.
残り二小節ラストスパート
Final two bars, the last spurt,
憧れの男ルパン三世 (Yay!)
the man of my dreams, Lupin the Third (Yay!)
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ
I've definitely claimed my prey!
はーい！ということで、グレートフルデイズとルパン・ザ・ファイヤーを続けて聞いていただきました！
Ha-i! So, you listened to "Grateful Days" and "Lupin the Fire" back-to-back!
グレートフルデイズはですね、えっと男性2人と女性1人の曲なんですけど、
"Grateful Days" is a song with two guys and one girl,
女性のところはね、絶対AZKiちゃんが良いってことでAZKiちゃん。
and for the female part, I definitely wanted AZKi-chan, so it's AZKi-chan.
で、ラップパートはもうノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったので、ノエルちゃんにお願いしました！二人ともありがとうございました！
And for the rap part, I could only picture Noel-chan's face, so I asked Noel-chan! Thank you both so much!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ここでもびっくりした！
And you know, Lupin's footage played and everyone must have been surprised, right? I was surprised here too!
で、今日のハッシュタグは、もうね、7周年だってすごいよね。この上のハッシュタグ「戌神ころね7周年」でぜひいっぱいつぶやいてください！スクショも大丈夫だよ。
And today's hashtag is—well, 7 years is amazing, right? Please tweet a lot with the hashtag above "Inugami Korone 7th Anniversary"! Screenshots are fine too.
ね、ここのステージ、なんかここはどこなんでしょうか？ どこ？
Hey, this stage—it feels a bit different today, but where on earth is this? Where?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
すてき！今日はイヌバレーからすべてお届けしますので、よろしくお願いします！
Lovely! Today we'll be delivering everything from Inu Valley, so please look forward to it!
って思ったけどさ、なんか画面小さくない？って思ってね、リザさんね。こうね、ちょっと思ったので、
But then I thought, isn't the screen a bit small? Or so I thought, Lisa-san. So I thought more about it, and
ちょっとね、あ、ちょっと待って！ なんか、字が持ってる、字が持ってる！ やめて！やばいやばい！
wait, wait! Hey, the characters are holding it, the characters are holding it! Stop! Oh no, oh no!
カプセルになっちゃうよこれ！ ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、画面を広く使いたいので、あっちいけ！
I'm going to turn into a capsule! Let's push it a bit, it's the Reiwa era now, so I want to use the screen widely, go away!
もうちょいどけ！ あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。こっちは？
Go further away! A bit more. Okay, okay, okay. What about this side?
あ、ちがっ... はい、そんなにころと言いたいのおいで！ 本当に来るんじゃないよ！本当に来るんじゃ...
Ah, wait... Hey, come here if you want to say that much to Korone! Don't actually come! Don't actually...
時計を早く
Make the clock go faster.
いた？
Was it there?
あいたね、なんだったんだろうね
It opened, I wonder what that was.
ということで、
So,
あ、なんか！ なんか落ちてきたよ！
Ah, something! Something's falling down!
花びらかなこれ
Is this a petal?
こっちから降ってきた？ ちょっと行ってみよう
Did it fall from over here? Let's check it out.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind that won't stop blowing, just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it
淡い香り戻ってくる
in the wind will come back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just as we were back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュールーラ ヒュールーラ
Hyuruu ra, hyuruu ra...
さくら散り出す 思い出す 意味なく
The cherry blossoms start to scatter, and I remember meaninglessly.
灯り出す あの頃また気になる
A light turns on, and again I think about back then.
変わらない香り景色風 違うのは君がいないだけ
The same scent, scenery, wind. The only difference is you're not here.
ここに立つと甦る こみ上げる記憶読み返す
Standing here revives memories, I read them over and over.
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Long hair dancing in the spring breeze, fussing over trivial things again.
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
Right under the cherry blossom tree, we talked and talked.
想い出は俺輝いた証だ
Memories are proof that I've shined.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ それでもここまで変わらぬままで
When the cherry blossoms fall, we meet and part. And yet, here I am, still the same.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals are falling. Memories are coming back.
気付けばまたこの季節で 君との想い出に誘われ
I find myself in this season again, lured by memories of you.
心の扉叩いた でも手をすり抜けた花びら
I opened the door of my heart, but the petals slipped through my hand.
初めて分かった 俺幼かった この場所来るまで分からなかった
I realized for the first time that I was young, I didn't understand until I came here.
此処だけは今も何故 運命のように香る風
But this is the only place where the wind smells like destiny.
暖かい日の光がこぼれる 目を閉じればあの日に戻れる
Warm sunlight spills over. I close my eyes and I can go back to that day.
いつしか君のおも影は 消えてしまうよ何処かへ
Someday your face will fade away... somewhere.
あの日以来景色変わらない 散りゆく花びらは語らない
The scenery hasn't changed since that day. The falling petals don't speak.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind that won't stop blowing, just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の 淡い香り戻ってくる
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it in the wind will come back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just as we were back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュールーラ ヒュールーラ
Hyuruu ra, hyuruu ra...
そっと僕の肩に 舞い落ちたひとひらの花びら
A petal of a flower gently falls on my shoulder.
手に取り目をつむれば 君が傍にいる
I take it in my hand and close my eyes, you're beside me.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind that won't stop blowing, just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の 淡い香り戻ってくる
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it in the wind will come back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just as we were back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュールーラ ヒュールーラ
Hyuruu ra, hyuruu ra...
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals are falling. Memories are coming back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry petals flutter down,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come dancing back.
タイムマシーンにのって
[Title: Riding in a Time Machine]
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people reach certain moments,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they say things like, "If I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 直せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, they really can't.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been that way forever, well, nothing we can do.
きっと先は深くて不安定
Surely ahead lies depth and uncertainty,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being too well-behaved is boring, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
Hop into the time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
if you can become a traveler,
箱の中の猫を思っても
even thinking of the cat inside the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret scorches your chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が冴ぎるんだわ
always, that suspicion blocks the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been that way forever, well, nothing we can do.
きっと先は深くて不安定
Surely ahead lies depth and uncertainty,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being too well-behaved is boring, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
Hop into the time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
if you can become a traveler.
どこをどうやってでもね
No matter how or where,
時間ってのは戻せない
time cannot be turned back.
レンズ越し未来にめがけてピースサイン伝えて 今のとかいい調子
Aiming through the lens toward the future, flashing a peace sign—things are going great right now.
青春の1ページも たったの1ページで
Even a page of youth, in just a single page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも 一夜きりのTweetのbuzzみたい
the highlight of your proud life is like a one-night-only tweet's buzz.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I remember the day I met you.
イヤフォンたらしてこの曲をきいていたよ
Listening to this song with earphones dangling.
あれから数えて今日は何年目!?
Counting from back then, how many years has it been today!?
今じゃ足跡どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
Now footprints remain everywhere, so this is a lyric card.
載せず鍵かけておこう #&S!'-= ほらね、聴き取れない!!
Let's keep it locked without posting... See, you can't hear it!
皆いつもしつこくよ悩み 締切に追われ歴史を作り
Everyone is always persistently troubled, chased by deadlines making history,
弱さを無理やり ごまかし君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
Forcibly hiding weakness—your lawn is green, it doesn't have to be blue.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
An idol caught in the midwinter sky,
政治家ぶれてブレちゃった帰り道
acting like a politician, stumbling on the way home.
とうちゃんローン組んだみはての先
Father took out a loan, out to the bitter end.
でも時は全部を流して
But time washes everything away.
人はこれって時にどうしても 「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
When people reach certain moments, no matter what, they say, "If I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 直せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, they really can't.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been that way forever, well, nothing we can do.
きっと先は深くて不安定
Surely ahead lies depth and uncertainty,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being too well-behaved is boring, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで トラベラーになれたら
Hop into the time machine, if you can become a traveler,
俺ってやつ発らいつも 気づいた時は手遅れ
a guy like me is always too late when he realizes.
絵空ごとばかり うつつ抜かして大事な人すら救えない
Losing myself in daydreams, unable to save even someone important.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かして あの時 あいつは多分気を使って
That's why I talk to myself with a song like this—back then, maybe he was being considerate,
特に顔色変えず なにもないふり
without changing his expression, pretending nothing was wrong.
なんでいないんだってムカついても やさしさからきてたならしょうがないね
Even if I get pissed off wondering why he's not here, if it came from kindness, it can't be helped.
願わくばディスコで父親と母親が会った日に行きたいね
I'd love to go back to the day my father and mother met at a disco.
後ろのジョックスに酒 かけて息子直々(じきじき)にチャンス作ってやるぜ
Pouring drinks on the jocks in the back, making a chance for my son myself.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ 始まりはこんな小さい歯車
No matter how huge the clock is, it all starts with such a small gear.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
Enough with the fine details, I'm tired.
別に怒ってないってさ 未来は
I'm not mad or anything, the future is...
人はこれって時にどうしても 「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
When people reach certain moments, no matter what, they say, "If I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 直せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, they really can't.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been that way forever, well, nothing we can do.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future ahead is deep and unstable,
でも行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but behaving well is boring, right?
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
Getting into the time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
if I could become a traveler...
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて街に飛び出した俺んた
Kicking open the Chevy's door, bursting into town, we are
暴力酒に女 音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面にゃ
Violence, liquor, women, music—flipping the bird at adults' masks!
Oh さあ踊ろう
Oh, come on, let's dance,
「今日」という日を生き急ぐメンバー
members rushing through the day called "today"!
足りねぇか？
Not enough?
Little louder!
欲望渦巻く路上分が現場
Streets swirling with desire are our stage!
Yeah いつだってそうだろう ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
Yeah, it's always been like that—The Blue Hearts, Ozaki, Eikichi are our textbooks.
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ 誓ったよあの放課後
Wanting to look cool until we drop, we swore it after school.
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん
We're Peter Pans—we must never say "maybe someday."
嘲笑う大人に言ってやらあ 人生はたったの一回だ
Tell those sneering adults: you only live once!
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chests, primal impulse.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye? No, no.
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering with scars—my way!
Go on! You should know who we are forever young
Forever Young hey! It's your turn next time from here
大切なことは魂の状態
What matters is the state of your soul.
その次の始めるべき時は今
The time to start the next thing is right now!
高笑いする都会の喧騒 ウケ狙いならば振り向け連荘
The sneering hustle and bustle of the city—if you want laughs, keep turning back!
何連呼？忘れる？夢流した便所 見下ろしてきがかる摩天楼
Chanting what? Forgetting? Look down at the skyscraper over the toilet where dreams washed away!
Oh まるで勝新みたいで破天荒 伝説へとアテンド
Oh, outrageous like Katsushinki, attending to legend.
怖にゃあ怖にゃあてその程度
"Scared, scared"? That's about it.
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away excuses and past glory!
永遠なんざねぇて いつか天へ召される天で
There's no such thing as forever; someday we'll be called to heaven.
ペンで書き殴ったこの魂は 2PACみたく誰かの心を通過
This soul scribbled with a pen passes through someone's heart like 2PAC.
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, haven't you forgotten something? Life is like a movie, everyone's an entertainer.
思い出せ思想は現実化する 誰かがHighway 飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts become reality—someone speeds on the highway in a Bentayga.
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chests, primal impulse.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye? No, no.
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering with scars—my way!
Go on! You should know who we are forever young
Hey! 俺たちは今日だって 若気の至りのような夢を追いかけて来た
Hey! Today too, we've been chasing youthful, reckless dreams.
Forever Young hey! 変わるはずなんてないさ さあ仕掛けてろ 今日は
Forever Young! Hey! There's no way it'll change—come on, set it up today!
残された人生で一番若い日だ
It's the youngest day of the rest of your life.
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな (永遠)
If your resolve is half-hearted, throw it in the gutter! (Forever)
往生際が悪いテメェ笑い飛ばし 誇れBetter days
Laugh off your poor grace, and be proud of better days.
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, I won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, I won't let it end until we drop! (Forever)
Forever Young もう夢を追いかけ 本気になった心は
Forever Young! Once you chase dreams and get serious,
自分の指図も受けない (永遠)
your heart won't even take orders from yourself! (Forever)
Forever Young hey! その思いから逃れられないなら
Forever Young! Hey! If you can't escape that feeling,
自ら向かうだけ (永遠)
just face it head-on! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, I won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, I won't let it end until we drop! (Forever)
まだ終わらない まだ終わらない Forever Young
It's not over yet, it's not over yet, Forever Young!
そう 今日という日は お前に残された人生の一番若い日
Yes, today is the youngest day of the life left to you.
なんだヤング？
What's up, youngin'?
うー
Ooh...
で、マリー、今日はね、今日はね
So, Marine, today, y'know, today...
ええ？
Eh?
後ろ見て？
Look behind you.
演奏してくれてる！
They're playing for us!
気まずいよ
It's so awkward!
今日はね
Today, y'know,
演奏してくれてるみんなが
everyone playing instruments for us
乗ってるよ
are getting into it!
乗ってるね、マリン、えー、ど、どれと写真撮りたい？
They are. Marine, wh-which one do you want to take a picture with?
え、そんな、え、1人だけみたいな、そんななんか
Eh, like, just one of them? Like that, something...
いや、二人選んでいい、二人選んでいい
No, you can pick two, you can pick two!
かわいそうじゃん、二人中
That's too bad, between the two...
二人選ぼう、二人選ぼう
Let's pick two, let's pick two!
俺もころね好きがなんか、最... いやでもマリンが選んだんだよ
I also... Korone-suki is like... Marine, you're the one choosing!
あ、マリンが、え、どう、どう？さい、じゃあ最初
Ah, Marine, eh, how, how? Sa-, then first...
あの、あ、待って、最初は？
Um, ah, wait, first is?
待って、映して、後ろ
Wait, show it, behind us.
みんな下向いて
Everyone, look down.
細犬さん
Hosainu-san!
かわいい、かわいい
Cute! So cute!
あ、じゃあ細犬、まずまず細犬と写真撮ろっか
Ah, then Hosainu, let's first take a picture with Hosainu!
かわいいよ
So cute!
細犬
Hosainu!
こっち、こっちおいでマリン、こっちにね
Come here, Marine, come over here.
はい、細犬です
Yes, I'm Hosainu.
ええと、細犬はギターかな？
Um, is Hosainu playing the guitar?
ギターですか？細犬ちゃん
Is that a guitar, Hosainu-chan?
ベロの色が
The color of its tongue
かわいいね、かわいいてるベロ
is so cute! A glowing tongue!
ベロかわいい、ちょっと死んでるんだけどベロの、あ、でもかわいい
The tongue is cute, though it looks a bit dead... ah, but it's cute!
うん、かわいいね、あんまり触らないでね
Yeah, it's cute. Don't touch it too much, okay?
ごめんね、いっぱい触って
Sorry for touching you so much!
え、次、誰がいい？
Eh, next, who do you want?
あと1人、あと1人
One more, one more!
じゃあ
Then...
太犬？
Futo-inu?
太犬
Futo-inu!
太犬だね
It's Futo-inu.
はい、太犬はドラムです
Yes, Futo-inu is on drums!
かわいい！
So cute!
でかい！
So big!
かわいいね
Cute, right?
ベロの色がちょっと明るい
The color of its tongue is a bit brighter
細犬より
than Hosainu's.
取った？みんな取った？
Did you take it? Did everyone take it?
取った！
Got it!
かわいい！
So cute!
オッケーだね？うん
That's good, right? Yeah.
オッケー
Okay!
え、じゃあ最後さ、二人でも撮ろうよ、二人でも
Eh, then finally, let's take one with both of us too!
あ、そうだね、二人でも撮ろう、二人でも
Ah, right, let's take one together!
撮れん
Can take it.
え？
Eh?
ちょっと
Wait...
あ、ん？
Ah, hm?
あ、ごめん、ごめん！やっぱりじゃあ、
Ah, sorry, sorry! Actually, then...
じゃあね、やっぱり取り直した方がいいのかな？
Then, y'know, should we re-take it after all?
あ、やっぱりね？
Ah, really?
コロネスキーともね
With Korone-sukis too,
撮りますか？
shall we take a picture?
コロネスキー、コロさん好き？
Korone-sukis, do you like Korosan?
好き？コロさん好き？
Do you like it? Do you like Korosan?
あ、がいい。え、マリンも好き？
Ah, that's good. Eh, does Marine like it too?
間に入ろう
Let's get in between!
なんでだよ！
Why's you say that?!
コロネスキーなのに、コロさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
How does it feel not being able to stand next to Korosan, even though you're a Korone-suki?
嬉しい？マリンが隣でね
Are you happy Marine is next to you?
嬉しくない！
I'm not happy!
本音は好きなんじゃないの？
Honestly, don't you like it?
やめい、やめろよ！だめもうだめ、帰るよ！
Stop it, cut it out! No, no more, I'm going home!
帰るよもう！はい帰ろう
I'm going home already! Okay, let's go back.
はい、今日はね、このバンドメンバーがいましたけれどもですね
Yes, today, we had these band members here,
ええ
yeah.
はい、え、マリンとも最後撮りたい
Yes, um, I want to take a picture with Marine at the end too.
あ、撮ろう撮ろう撮ろう
Ah, let's take it, let's take it!
せっかくね、ホエールヤングだから今日は
Since it's Whale Young today,
ね、マイク、マイク
Hey, mic, mic!
マイク持って
Hold the mic!
マイク、間違っちゃった
Mic... I got it wrong!
間違えちゃってるけどさ、マイクね
I made a mistake, but hey, the mic, you know.
うん、いいよ、いいよ
Yeah, it's fine, it's fine.
でかい声で喋るのは広いから、ね、こうして
Talking with a big voice echoes because it's spacious, like this.
取れた？
Did you get it?
行けてる？太犬、太犬
Is it working? Futo-inu, Futo-inu!
中心としてハート
Making a heart centered around...
え、かわいい子取れたね？
Eh, we got a cute picture, right?
うん、ありがとマリン
Yeah, thanks, Marine!
ありがとう
Thank you!
じゃあね、ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど、うん
Well then, we have the next song coming up, so we'll go, yeah.
次の曲、うん
Next song, yeah.
1人で帰れる？
Can you go back by yourself?
おお、え、え、大丈夫、うんうん、大丈夫大丈夫大丈夫
Oh, eh, it's fine, yeah, it's fine!
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく
Then, please take care of the band members.
え？
Eh?
じゃあ、マリン、ばいばい！
Then, Marine, bye-bye!
え？よろしくって何よ？
Eh? What do you mean "take care of"?
どんなムードこれ？あ、え？
What kind of mood is this? Ah, eh?
あ、みんな、あ、あ、そして
Ah, everyone, ah, and then...
みんな、次の曲で、えーっと...
everyone, for the next song, um...
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
Ways to slack off, ways to lean on others, ways to run away, ways to make excuses...
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た
I've finally learned them, I've finally acquired them.
柔らかい頭
A soft and flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 女子のこき方 腹のすえ方 いい歳のこき方
How to look cool, how to work women, how to steel oneself, how to act one's age...
胆乗りに乗った 濁った飯屋 だらしない体
Riding the momentum, visiting murky eateries, a sloppy body...
嫌われ方や 脅われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, how to be feared, how to scold, how to clash cleanly...
もっと覚えたことが 山のようにある
There are still mountains of things I want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
I've got so much room to grow!
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ 悪者使い
We still have nothing but room to grow! Treating people like villains...
悪者扱い 慣れてきたマジで 悪者扱い 慣れてきたオトナへ
Treating people like villains, I've really gotten used to it. To an adult used to being treated as a villain,
変わりゆく俺 鏡の中へ
changing me, into the mirror...
訪ねても来ないなら yeah yeah yeah
If no one even comes to visit, yeah yeah yeah...
去る者追わない
I won't chase those who leave.
糸口引いて 丸くおさめた
Pulling the clue, settling things peacefully.
ちゃるくイナして 鏡の中で
Casually deflecting, inside the mirror.
ふわボケるお前 くぐれやしなかった門 たったの3文字で
A fuzzy, dazed you—the gate I couldn't pass through, in just three letters...
日々を黙る足取りで 自分の歩幅で歩してる
Walking with quiet steps day by day, walking at my own pace.
カマすところカマす マカすところマカす 割と適当な段取りで
Striking where I should strike, defeating where I should defeat, with a rather casual setup,
やっと分かって来たかも
I've finally started to understand, maybe.
今日のポンコツの操縦の仕方を 19の時のついに聞いた戒め
How to pilot this day's incompetence—a warning I finally heard at 19:
もっとすがすがしい気持ち
"A more refreshing feeling,"
隅田川にかかる 勝鬨橋をわたる
crossing Kachidoki Bridge over the Sumida River.
左手にスカイツリー 右手に東京タワー
Skytree on the left, Tokyo Tower on the right,
俺はその真ん中
and I am right in the middle!
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
Ways to slack off, ways to lean on others, ways to run away, ways to make excuses...
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た
I've finally learned them, I've finally acquired them.
柔らかい頭
A soft and flexible mind.
カッコの
How to look...
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
How to look cool, how to get carried away, how to steel your nerve, how to get carried away at a good age
脂乗りに乗った 似合っ得た飯食った
Riding high on success, eating well-deserved meals
だらしない体だ
Having such a sloppy body
幸せの体感速度は 早くなるばかり
The perceived speed of happiness only gets faster
傷が癒えていく速度は 遅くなるばかり
The speed at which wounds heal only gets slower
他人に期待をしないのが 今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my strength right now
手負いでも進める距離なら
If it's a distance I can advance even while wounded
威張る威張る 身のほど知るほどに
I boast and boast, as I realize my station
胸を張り いつも通り
Puffing out my chest, as always
でも時にしたていぜのび やっと大人げないが出来る歳 小さな枠組み
But sometimes showing off, at an age where I can finally afford to be un-adult-like, in a small framework
ただの数字 縛られずに
Just numbers, without being bound
でも腹くくり あの日の俺が立ち止まる
Yet resolving myself, the me of that day stops in my tracks
ほどにでかくそびえ立つ 隅田川にかかる
Towering massively, spanning the Sumida River
勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing Kachidoki Bridge
重なるスカイツリー 東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
The overlapping Skytree, Tokyo Tower, and the unreliable back in the middle
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言訳の仕方とか やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた 柔りゃいいやとまあ
How to slack off, how to act spoiled, how to run away, how to make excuses... I've finally learned them, acquired them, thinking soft is fine
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
How to look cool, how to get carried away, how to steel your nerve, how to get carried away at a good age
脂乗りに乗った 似合っ得た飯食った
Riding high on success, eating well-deserved meals
だらしない体だ 嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
Having such a sloppy body. How to be disliked, how to be adored, how to scold, how to clash gracefully
覚えたことが山の様にある
There are mountains of things I've learned
のびしろしかないわ ワンワンワンわ のびしろしかないわ... 俺まだのびしろしかないわ
There's nothing but room to grow, woof woof woof woof, there's nothing but room to grow... I still have nothing but room to grow!
ばかまじめ
[Title: Bakamajime]
くだらない話と
Worthless conversations
うざったい貴様と
And annoying you
なみなみの日々に 注がれてく
Pouring into these brimming days
怠いが溢れ出していく
Sluggishness overflows
飯がまだ届かない
Food still hasn't arrived
仕事は片付かない
Work isn't finished
うだつの上がらない 毎日にため息ばかり
Sighing every day with nothing to show for it
でまた派手にすっころび
Then falling flat on my face spectacularly again
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
Spilling coffee on a freshly washed shirt
前のめりの姿勢だけは褒めて良し 肩を落とし並木通り増えた柄と差し色に
Only the forward-leaning posture is praise-worthy. Dropping my shoulders on the tree-lined avenue, with increased patterns and accent colors
嗚呼… 本当嫌んなる毎日だ
Ah... what a truly miserable everyday life
やりたくないことやったって 嫌々早起きしたって
Even if I do things I don't want to do, even if I wake up early reluctantly
その分素敵な何かが 訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
It's not like something wonderful will visit me for that reason, yet
今日もまた頑張っちゃうような がむしゃら以外知らないから
I only know how to recklessly push forward, so I'll do my best again today
不器用で 意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
Blessings to us clumsy, stubborn, and foolishly earnest folks
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Putting down my heavy luggage for a moment to stop
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまいば同じ
If I forget about yesterday, it's all the same
浴びるdaylight 羽根伸ばし それか月夜にこっそり吐き出してしまえば良い
Bathe in daylight, spread your wings, or quietly spit it out in the moonlight
でもその前にアレとコレの話 その為にはまずはそれを片付け 今は何時?
But before that, let's talk about this and that. To do that, first let's clear that up. What time is it now?
いやその前に 今日もなんだかんだ騒ましい毎度あり
No, before that, today is rowdy as usual, thank you very much
1ヶ月くらい何にも 考えずだらだらしていたいな
I'd like to loaf around without thinking about anything for about a month
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいなって思う日もあるけれど
Though there are days when I think I just want to rest, play, and sleep lazily
やっとここまで来たんだよ
I've finally come this far
ここじゃ終れないんだよ
I can't end it here
辛いきついもいつかは 笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
Look, I believe that whatever painful or tough times there are can someday be turned into a funny story
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
So I'll do my best again today
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ 目一杯吸い込んだ空気
Singing love recklessly, taking in a lungful of air
ああ 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, what a truly wonderful everyday life
やりたくないことやったって 嫌々早起きしたって
Even if I do things I don't want to do, even if I wake up early reluctantly
ほんの少しの幸せに触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんださ
Just touching a tiny bit of happiness makes everything feel worth it
明日もまた頑張ってみようか がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
Shall I try my best again tomorrow? I'll live life recklessly
不器用で 意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
Blessings to us clumsy, stubborn, and foolishly earnest folks
do my thing do your thing 肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
do my thing do your thing, relaxing my shoulders flexibly
do my thing do your thing あと1ミリ背伸び
do my thing do your thing, stretching just 1 millimeter taller
ああ 本当嫌んなっちゃうな それでも今を生きてい
Ah, what a truly miserable thing. Yet I am living right now
不器用で 意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
Blessings to you, clumsy, stubborn, and foolishly earnest person
Longiness
[Title: Longiness]
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
No matter how much I struggle to be like them,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて君の心に落とすimagination
Nickel Burn, light a fire, imagination dropping into your heart.
キリキリでフライできず地獄送りさ 君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えようか
Unable to fly on the edge, sent straight to hell. Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心揺らされ近道した結果 誰かの後をつけてるだけだったからさ
It was because you took a shortcut swayed by props, just following someone else's footsteps.
未だわからないか最初は気づいてた
Still don't get it? You noticed at first.
知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
Pretended not to know and told yourself it was your own path.
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと 過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
Can't fool others if you don't play your own original. Dragged down by your past self, you exit.
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between you and me is on a genetic level.
俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる さらに磨き上げ自分自身にも感謝してる
I'm grateful to the parents and grandparents who drove me mad. I'm also grateful to myself.
なのだんなことしてる君差が離れてくうちに
Yet while you're doing whatever, the distance between us grows...
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
Feeling despair, you'll quit rap anyway.
5年後いや4年後これは余命宣告 現状に満足してばっでんの?
5 years from now, no, 4 years from now, this is a death sentence. Satisfied with the status quo?
俺らは発展途上でもかっけえぞ
Even as works in progress, we look cool.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
No matter how much I struggle to be like them, I sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて君の心に落とすimagination
Nickel Burn, light a fire, imagination dropping into your heart.
恋い焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達 上べだけのお友達じゃお前の子と甘やかす
Yearned-for men and women who defied time. Superficial friends just spoil who you are.
命削りぬらりくらり情熱だけ注ぐ歌詞 現実に頬濡らす理想達が雨降らす
Lyrics pouring only passion, reality getting ideals wet with rain.
あれもカスこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす
Trash is trash, turning heads with my lyrics.
浮きになって無視したって知らぬうちに街を這う 体揺らし声を鳴らしたって誰も聞いてない
Ignoring it and creeping through the streets. Shaking my body and voice, but nobody's listening.
導かれて聞いてみても耳は糸を引いてない 今日と明日あさっても白紙の中あさって
Even if guided and listening, my ears aren't pulled. Today, tomorrow, day after on blank paper.
思想すらも曲がってるだけど顔は笑って 嘘だらけの肥溜めで登れるまで使って
Even thoughts are warped, but my face is smiling. Using lies to climb this cesspool.
空に祈り捧げたって変れるのは声だけ
Only voice can change what's offered to the sky.
何かあれば孤独気取りむしり取るかね 指でこすりめくり表見れば裏探すだけ
Whatever happens, acting lonely, tearing it away. Rubbing my fingers, looking at the front, searching the back.
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴も全て愛で砕けて もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない全部お前のせい
Useless complaints crushed by love. I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore, all your fault.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
No matter how much I struggle to be like them, I sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて君の心に落とすimagination
Nickel Burn, light a fire, imagination dropping into your heart.
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi...
俺たち何? え? チーム友達
Who are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東 、北南
Kansai, Kanto, West, East, North, South
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 俺たち何? え? チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi... Who are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
お好み焼き 食う鶴橋 腹いっぱい 飯はうまい
Eating okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi, belly full, food is good
1人じゃ寂しい時もあるたりや 掛け直したあとすぐいく相槌
Sometimes lonely, calling back right away with an acknowledgment
TEAMTOMODACHI
T E A M T O M O D A C H I
チーム友達 祭り愛
Team Tomodachi, love for festivals
ちぎり乾し飲んでる酒ちぎり
Drying chigiri, drinking sake, chigiri
CHIGIRI CHIGIRI CHIGIRI CHIGIRI CHIGIROU CHIGIROU CHIGIROU CHIGIROU
CHIGIRI CHIGIRI CHIGIROU CHIGIROU
ちぎり ちぎり ちぎり ちぎり ちぎろう ちぎろう ちぎろう ちぎろう
Chigiri, chigiri, chigirou, chigirou
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何? え? チーム友達
Who are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東 、北南 チーム友達 チーム友達
Kansai, Kanto, West, East, North, South, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達、チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Eh? Team Tomodachi
チーム友達、チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
いぇーい！ よーよーよー
Yeah! Yo-yo-yo-
勝手に撮ってんじゃねぇ！ よー！
Don't just take pictures without asking! Yo!
え、見てんのか？ あ、ごめん、見てんのかよー！
Eh, you watching? Oh sorry, you watching!
おーい、ガラが悪いぜよー！
Hey, you look so rough!
ちょっと、この帽子とかのせいで、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね
Because of these hats and stuff, we look a bit like punks, but
うん、かっこいいじゃん！ こんなかっこいつかしてみたいと思ったんだよ！
Yeah, it's cool! I always wanted to dress like this!
これバチクソ高いからこれ気をつけて。
This is super expensive, so be careful.
え、本当にね、今日ね着たらね、これ用意してあるんで、え？なにこれって。
When I wore it today, this was prepared, so like "Wh-what is this?"
重たいでしょ。
It's heavy, right.
うん、重たいでもかっこいい。
Yeah, it's heavy, but cool.
あのロックりみたいになってるから今、うちら。
It's like rock-and-roll right now, us.
おもりつけてるからね、今。解き放たれたらもっと動けるからね。
We're wearing weights right now. If unleashed, we can move more.
そう、外したらね、いい感じになりますけど。
Yeah, once we take it off, it'll feel good.
えでも、ころねさん、週ねおめでとうございます！
Eh but, Korone-san, happy 7th anniversary!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ねぇ、7周年だよ！こうね。
Hey, it's the 7th anniversary! Korone.
ねぇ、すごくない？ 本当にね。 え、待って、みこちゃんの衣装を見て！
Right, isn't it amazing? Truly. Eh wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit!
これ誕生日で、はい、着たやつね。
This is what I wore for my birthday, yeah.
はい、え、後ろを向いて、後ろも！
Yeah, eh, turn around, the back too!
今回用意してくれたこの装飾に、なんかマッチしてて草なんだけど、めっちゃマッチしてます。
It matches the decoration prepared this time so much it's hilarious, it matches so well.
え、でもそれ言うとさ、この衣装さ、ゲマズのイベントのやつなんだけどさ。
Eh, but speaking of which, this outfit is from the Gamers event.
ほらちょうちょちょちょうゲマズの、衣装、かわいいじゃん！
Look, super super Gamers, the outfit is cute!
みこちゃん今日ね、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is the very first time unveiling this outfit.
これでチーム友達でちょっと初お披露目しちゃったんですけど
With this, we debuted it a bit for Team Tomodachi, but
え、いいじゃんいいじゃんいいよ！ かわいい、ちょっと短くない？
Eh, that's fine, that's good! Cute, isn't it a bit short?
え、そうなん？ これめちゃ短いんだよね？ 大丈夫？
Eh really? This is super short, right? Is it okay?
まるみえね、これ！ 見せろのよ！
It's totally visible, this! Show it off!
え、これ大丈夫かな？
Eh, is this okay?
しかもね、こうねなんかさ、めちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。
And also Korone, someone said my chest looks super tight, this.
いや、なんかちょっとシワができちゃってるの、パツパツで。弾け飛びそうだよ、なんか。
Well, kind of wrinkles formed because it's so tight. Looks like it's about to burst.
多分ね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う。
Probably the size doesn't fit, I think.
あー、でもそのぐらいがね、いいですからね。え、じゃあ写真撮りたい！
Ah, but that much is good. Eh, then I want to take a picture!
写真撮りたい！ちょっとアップめで撮りたいんだよな。
I want to take a picture! I want to take it close-up.
いいね、うん。えじゃ、しゃがもうよ。しゃがむか？
Sounds good, yeah. Eh then, let's squat. Shall we squat?
よー。
Yo.
よー。お、いいじゃん！
Yo. Oh, nice!
スパイダーマンみたいなちょっと。
Like Spider-Man a bit.
よー、よー。
Yo, yo.
サングラスもさ、取ってさ
Take off the sunglasses too
よいしょ、よいしょ。ちょっと待ってね、みんなね。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Wait a second everyone.
行くよ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, go!
はい、あ、いいじゃんいいじゃん！ アップめで撮る？
Yeah, oh nice nice! Take it close-up?
アップめで撮りたい、イエーイ！ あ、じゃあカメラをね、いただきましたね。
I want to take a close-up, yeah! Oh, then we received the camera.
アダオー！
Adao!
イエーイ！
Yay!
撮れてる？チーム友達！ チーム友達！
Are you taking it? Team Tomodachi! Team Tomodachi!
え、どこを歌うねん！
Eh, what are you singing!
え、でもさ、この曲さ、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
Eh, but you know, I was happy you chose this song.
やっぱチーム友達って言うぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて。
It's a song called Team Tomodachi, so I wanted to sing it with a friend.
だから誰でもよかったんだけど、別に友達だからみんな。
So anyone was fine, because everyone's a friend.
おい！うそ、うそ！ 特にみこみこと歌いたかった！
Hey! No, no! Especially I wanted to sing with Miko-miko!
あー、ありがとってか、チーム友達だから、当たり前じゃん。
Ah, thanks, I mean since we're team tomodachi, of course.
チーム友達だから、当たり前じゃん！
Because we're team tomodachi, of course!
え、でも、あ、そろそろね、次の曲なんじゃないですか？
Eh, but, ah, isn't it almost time for the next song?
あ、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くんだよ、なんなだけど。
Ah, a little more, it continues just a little bit more, though.
うん。え、次どんな感じなの？
Yeah. Eh, what's the next one like?
え、次はね、あの、パンツです！
Eh, the next one is, um, PANTS!
え？パンツ？パンツ？
Eh? Pants? Pants?
恥ずかしい。やめて！取らないで！
Embarrassing. Stop it! Don't take it!
え、だってみこと、この穿いてる、パンツってこと？
Eh, but look, this, you mean the pants you're wearing?
え、みこさん、穿いてないの？
Eh, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any?
え？みこさん穿いてないの、パンツ？
Eh? Miko-san aren't you wearing pants?
安心してください。
Don't worry.
穿いてますよ！
I'm wearing them!
穿いてる？あ、よかったじゃん。
Wearing them? Oh, that's good then.
え、コーネはまだこれからなのだよ、パンツ。
Eh, Korone is still from now on, pants.
え、え？入ってないってこと？
Eh, eh? You're not wearing them?
コーネはちょっとこれからなのだの。
Korone is a bit from now on.
ごめん、みこみこ。あの、これからだからコーネパンツ。
Sorry Miko-miko. Um, since it's from now, Korone's pants.
え、パンツ、パンツ？
Eh, pants, pants?
PANTS
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked, bow, wear it, pants!
アニマル、ネッキー、ニート、ネッキー、ピポ、ネッキー、bow, wear it, pants!
Animal, Nekky, NEET, Nekky, Pipo, Nekky, bow, wear it, pants!
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked, bow, wear it, pants!
No punch, no fight, no punch, no steal, no punch, no night
Bow, wear it, pants!
キュキュネイキッド キュキュネイキッド キュキュネイキッド
Kick you naked, kick you naked, kick you naked
king king king king
Don't worry, don't flex,
Don't worry,
Be naked, bow where it's tough,
Animal,
Naked, nature, naked, people,
Naked, bow where it's tough,
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex,
Don't worry, be naked, bow where it's tough,
You said naked, I said no,
I said naked, you said no,
You are wearing, I said tough, I said wearing, you take,
King, king, king, king,
Cyber, push, cyber, push,
I'm wearing pants, but I can't post naked!
Ah listen up,
キラッと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
A mouth suited for sparkling fangs tells the tale,
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
a smoky story woven by lyrical billows.
Let me see...
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
Wandering, draped in uncertain peace and anxiety,
十色の価値観 騒ぐラディカル 何がはじまる？ 不器用な生き様に心痺む
ten-colored values, a noisy radical—what starts?
青いな理性を欠いたサヴァイブ 願っても願ってもなくなれない
So naive, surviving without reason, won't disappear.
青いな盲目的ハイなマイライフ Do it again, do it again
Blind, high-life, do it again, do it again.
Chase, chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉
Chase, chase, where is my utopia, force open the door.
Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな ぐしゃぐしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる
Viva, break the status quo, hop on.
しわついたまま時を刻む（踊れ）
carving time while still wrinkled, dance.
数多のお目目から逃げた Back in the day ひた隠しているファンキーなヘッド
Back in the day, hiding a funky head.
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
A gift of individuality seems like a bug.
伏し目を逸らし 行く当てもない 現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
Lowering my eyes, deadlock with no way out.
抱いても泣いても買いても Fall... 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Embracing, crying, falling... chewing and swaying.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey don't panic, go too far far far, step forward, animal.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Hey don't panic, go too far far far, super far ahead.
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Critical Critical Criti Criti Criti
WIP aww WIP aww, Critical Critical Criti...
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, scheduled harmony.
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Yielding to fresh despair, pulling wrong moves.
手招く反逆のアイコン 一抹の不安抱くも遥遠 平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰歩けば Dope Dope Dope
An icon of rebellion beckons, Dope Dope Dope.
山積みトラブルに追い払われ呆れ やさくれ魘れにはなむけ発砲 (BANG!) ぶち抜く不条理 ヘッドぱんぱん
Driven by trouble, a farewell gunshot (BANG!).
出る杭嘘のニへしのプライド まみれのネミに見舞うヤバイもん 狂った情熱に冷え切った体温 上げるこのエナジーは文字通りゼイオン
Frozen body temp, this energy is literally Zion.
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たいDogsのお通りだ (Goooo!)
Smoky Dogs catching fire come through (Goooo!).
皆誰もがスペシャルの存在てこと忘れた結果
The result of forgetting everyone is special.
自分と違う箇所否定して笑えばねる それこそ欠陥 たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚 一向にならない愚かなるBattle
Denying different parts is a flaw, facing contradictions.
悲惨 失踪 闘争 Never never end 散らばる Hollow
Tragedy, disappearance, conflict, never end, Hollow.
ぎらり切り出しの牙と悪感が絡み合う 消灯 深い夜と歌う
Sparkling fangs intertwine, singing with the night.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey don't panic, go too far far far, animal.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Hey don't panic, go too far far far, super ahead.
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Critical Critical Criti Criti Criti WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Don't panic, Go too far far far
WIP aww WIP aww, Critical Critical...
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a job polished intently.
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
Today, a hazy future in the telescope.
いつかのオメルタもスーペニア
Someday's omerta is a souvenir.
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
My whereabouts melts the frozen heart.
マフィオーザ 祝砲を放つ (Yeah) アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク
Mafiosa, firing a salute, Eine kleine Nachtmusik.
ぐずった顔はグッバイ マフィオーザ 祝福の歌 (Yeah)
A sulky face is goodbye, song of blessing.
ようやく見付けた 掛け替えのない居場所 Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
An irreplaceable place, say hoo, let's dance.
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's keep dancing together.
ようやく見付けた ふたつとない居場所
An incomparable place to belong I finally found.
ようやく気付けた ふたつない居場所
I've finally realized the only place where I belong.
みんな、マフィオーサライブ初お披露目、どうだった？
Everyone, how was the very first reveal of the "Mafiosa" live?
ちょっと、「パンツ」と「マフィオーサ」で2曲続けてだったんですけど
We went with two songs in a row, "Pantsu" and "Mafiosa."
このね、「パンツ」って曲めちゃめちゃ好きで、あのずっと暇のとき
But you know, I really love the song "Pantsu," and whenever I had free time,
めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、今回歌えて嬉しいのと、コロネスキーにねピンクのパンツを履いて踊ってもらえたのがすごく嬉しかったので、みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
I listened to it all the time, so I'm so happy I got to sing it this time, and I was so thrilled to have Koronesuki wear pink pants and dance along—thank you everyone for dancing!
でね、今回、えっと「マフィオーサ」のライブ初お披露目をしたくて、全部ねラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、
And you know, this time, um, since I wanted to do the first-ever live reveal of "Mafiosa," I put together all rap songs,
どうだったかな？ちょっと初めての試みだったから、
and I wonder how it went? Since it was my first time trying this,
すごいね、あの準備段階から今日に至るまでめっちゃドキドキで、なんかみんな楽しんでくれるかなとか思ってたんだけど、
I was super nervous from the preparation stage all the way up to today, wondering if everyone would enjoy it or not.
だからね、みんなが楽しんでノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
So I'd be so happy if everyone had fun and got into the groove!
でね、原曲知らないよっていう方がね、結構いると思うんですけど、結構はないか、いると思うんですけど、
And you know, for those who might not know the original songs—well, maybe not quite a lot, but I'm sure there are some—
もしね、そういう方はぜひめっちゃめちゃかっこいいのでね、全部の曲原曲ぜひ聴いてみてください。
if you are one of them, please check out the original songs because they're all super cool!
あ、最後に歌った「マフィオーサ」もですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲かっこいいので、ぜひみんな聴いてね！
Oh, and "Mafiosa," which I sang last, also has an insanely cool original version, so please go listen to it!
はい、ということで今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちら！
Right, so we also have this time! Anniversary merch! Here it is!
え、今回はですね、なんと、うすた京介先生に描き下ろしていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Um, this time, remarkably, Kyosuke Usuta-sensei drew illustrations for us! Thank you so much!
一つずつ見ていきますかね。
Let's take a look at them one by one, shall we?
え、最初はですね、「YB-2」久しぶりに出しました。うちのブランド「YB-2」です。「YB-2」の、え、うすた先生バージョンのねパーカーです。
Um, first is "YB-2," which we're releasing after a long while. It's our brand "YB-2." This is the "YB-2" hoodie featuring Usuta-sensei's version.
え、裏面に、え、イラストが来る感じですね。で、胸元に「YB-2」って入ってて、腕にね、あの、ころねのモチーフの骨が入っております。これめちゃめちゃかっこいいと思うのでね、お楽しみに！
Um, the illustration is on the back. "YB-2" is on the chest, and on the arms, there's Korone's motif, a bone. I think this is super cool, so please look forward to it!
あ、続いてこちら！こちらはですね、あの、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです。ま、結構ね、なんかエクスポとかフェスとか、なんかみんなのねイベントとかに来るときにサコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って、
Ah, next is this! This is a sacoche with the same illustration as the hoodie. You know, I've seen quite a few people using sacoches when coming to expos, festivals, and everyone's events,
ころねもサコッシュ出したいということでサコッシュも出しました！みんないっぱい使ってください！
so I wanted to release a sacoche too, and here it is! Please use it a lot, everyone!
続いてこちら！こちらはですね、えっと、ごめんなさいね。え、ラップドックキャップ！こちらはですね、え、ひこさん先生のデザインで、あの出させていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Next is this! This is, um, sorry about that. The "Rap Dog Cap"! This was designed by Hikosan-sensei, and we're releasing it! Thank you so much!
え、ここにね、ころねの骨がクロスしてて、横にまたこれ「YB-2」です。これもう「YB-2」なのでね。サコッシュと、あ、サコッシュも、あ、サコッシュも「YB-2」か。パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、全部「YB-2」のブランドでございまーす！よろしくお願いします！
Um, Korone's bones are crossed here, and on the side, it's "YB-2" again. This is also "YB-2." The sacoche is—wait, is the sacoche "YB-2" too? Hoodie, sacoche, and hat are all from the "YB-2" brand! Please check them out!
はい、次！これは「YB-2」じゃない、ころねのランダムラバーーストラップ！こちらはね、フカヒレママに描き下ろしてもらいました！ママありがとうございます！
Next! This is not "YB-2," but Korone's random rubber strap! This was drawn by Fuka-mama! Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで。で、今回ねラップの曲が多かったということで、あのラップをしてるね、ころねのイラストもありますので、ぜひ皆さんに全種類目指してよかったら買ってきてみてください。通常衣装と、「YB-2」のジャンプスーツと、ドック、え、グッズドック衣装と、ラップ衣装ですね。よかったら、はい、こちらもご検討ください！
There are 4 random types. Since there were many rap songs this time, there are also illustrations of Korone rapping, so I hope you'll aim for all types and buy them if you'd like. There's the default outfit, the "YB-2" jumpsuit, the "Good Dog" outfit, and the rap outfit. Please consider getting these too, if you like!
そしてフルセットの購入特典は、え、うすた先生描き下ろしのですね、ポストカード。数量限定版もありますけれども、めちゃめちゃ、あの用意しておりますので、あの急がないで大丈夫です。あのマジで、結構用意したので、あのゆっくりご購入ください。
And the full set purchase bonus is a postcard newly illustrated by Usuta-sensei. There's also a limited quantity version, but we've prepared plenty of them, so you don't need to rush. Seriously, we prepped quite a lot, so please take your time purchasing.
はい、で通常バージョンはですね、箔押しの複製サイン入りとなっております。
And the regular version comes with a foil-stamped replica autograph.
はい、ということで今回のライブもみんなたくさん観てくれてありがとうございました！
Right, so thank you so much everyone for watching today's live as well!
以上、レイジードックナイトでした！みんな本当にいつもありがとね！また会おう！またねー！
That was "Lazy Dog Night"! Thank you all so much as always! See you again! Bye-bye!
Doggy Doggy God's Street
Listen up yeah
One, two, three, four
戌神Doggy メチャドープなMC
Inugami doggy, my dope MC
このエリア切ってのかなりハード
This area, it's quite hard
身の丈通りイチコロさ (Hell yeah)
One shot, one kill (hell yeah)
噛みついてくる荒くれも皆まとめて仲間へとアップデート
Even the rough ones who bite, I make them my friends and update them
ほら尻尾振ってご機嫌に Rock the beat
Hey, wag your tail and rock the beat nicely
調子いいね I wanna swing (Come on)
The feeling's good, I wanna swing (come on)
猛獣ひしめくストリートすら顔パス
Even in the street filled with beasts, I walk with ease
East sideからWest sideまで縄張りだから (Watch out)
From the East Side to the West Side, it's my territory (watch out)
ムチムチいきり優しくぶっとばす
Tough, tough, gently I blow them away
Let you know my rule 戌神ころね
Let you know my rule, Inugami Korone
Oh yeah! Get out of my way
ヒヒAwooあるいはClap your hands
Hihi, awoo, or clap your hands
Oh yeah! 修練なパーティ
Oh yeah! The skillful party
ヒヒAwooあるいは行こうにWag your tail
Hihi, awoo, or let's go wag your tail
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words ありのままさ
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words, just as I am
ワンワンワンダーダダダー振るなこの生き様
Wan-wan-wan, da-da-da, don't shake this way of life
掴んだら離さないOne chanceで輝く (ヒャハー)
Once I grab it, I won't let go, shining in one chance (hya-ha)
I'm a絶対的霊験あらたかなDoggy God
I'm a definitive, miraculous, doggy god
世界中席巻イヌコック計画
The world is conquered, Doggy Kingdom plan
年が年中偉く世渡りす
Year after year, I'm the one who stands out
アヌビスにフェンリル、ケルベロス
Anubis, Fenrir, Cerberus
噛むし強いオルトロス皆アミーゴ
Even the cute Orthrus are all my amigos
On & On, 億こと間違いなし半端ない仕上がりの牙
On and on, no doubt, the finish of my fangs is no joke
キラキラでブリンブリンMy vibes
Sparkling, bling-bling, my vibes
飛翔仕果てる背犬のように
Like a soaring, soaring, dog-god
North sideからSouth sideまで網羅するヤカラ (What's up)
From the North Side to the South Side, all covered (what's up)
タッチタッチ一気に風のようにすっ飛ばす
Tough, tough, in an instant, I blow them away like the wind
Let you know my groove 戌神ころね
Let you know my groove, Inugami Korone
Oh yeah! Get out of my way
ヒヒAwooあるいはClap your hands
Hihi, awoo, or clap your hands
Oh yeah! 修練なパーティ
Oh yeah! The skillful party
ヒヒAwooあるいは行こうにWag your tail
Hihi, awoo, or let's go wag your tail
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words ありのままさ
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words, just as I am
ワンワンワンダーダダダー振るなこの生き様
Wan-wan-wan, da-da-da, don't shake this way of life
掴んだら離さないOne chanceで輝く (ヒャハー)
Once I grab it, I won't let go, shining in one chance (hya-ha)
I'm a絶対的霊験あらたかなDoggy God
I'm a definitive, miraculous, doggy god
Alright, 鎖につながれるなんてまっ平ごめんあそばせ
Alright, I refuse to be chained up
Awoo遠吠え一発で十戒の如く森羅万象が満ちあふれる
With one howl, like a miracle, the whole universe is filled
Glory to Dog, いかにも常軌逸したI'm so fly
Glory to Dog, I'm so fly, way beyond common sense
一切合切おまかせあれDoggy Doggy God
All in all, leave it to the doggy, doggy god
勇犬軍バイバイベイビーデーガーDoggy Doggy God
Good-bye to the brave army, baby, doggy, doggy god
当然今日も疾風怒涛Doggy Doggy God
Naturally, today too, with full speed, doggy, doggy god
Clap your hands, Wag your tail, On & On...
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words ありのままさ
Bow-wow-wow! Louder than words, just as I am
ワンワンワンダーダダダー振るなこの生き様
Wan-wan-wan, da-da-da, don't shake this way of life
掴んだら離さないOne chanceで輝く (ヒャハー)
Once I grab it, I won't let go, shining in one chance (hya-ha)
I'm a絶対的霊験あらたかなDoggy God
I'm a definitive, miraculous, doggy god